Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Unit 01's interlocking circuits have been cut.
What about the force eject signal?
It's being blocked from the plug side.
It's not being accepted.
But, Shinji, if we hadn't done that,
you would have been killed.
That doesn't matter.
But it is a fact.
Don't make me more angry
by saying things like that.
Unit 01 has 185 seconds of power
left in its reserves.
That's enough to destroy at least
half of Headquarters.
The way he is right now, he'll do it too.
Shinji, listen to us!
If Commander Ikari hadn't made that decision,
everyone could have been killed!
I said that doesn't matter!
My father...
That bastard tried to kill Toji!
With my hands...
EPISODE 19
A MAN'S BATTLE
Father, you're there, aren't you?
Say something! Answer me!
Increase the pressure of the LCL to maximum.
We have no time to waste on a childish tantrum.
I've still got a direct control circuit...
Damn! Damn!
Damn...
The right breast has been completely dissolved.
We'll begin cleansing the bodily fluids
from Unit 03 on schedule.
Have you recovered?
As long as I can work, it's not a problem.
I couldn't just lie in bed during
an emergency like this.
So what happened to Shinji?
I understand that they opened the
escape hatch with a laser cutter,
and removed him forcibly.
That's just wonderful.
This time...
It might really be over.
I'll bet that idiot won't recover from this.
How is Ikari?
He wasn't injured, so he ought to be okay.
He's probably dreaming away.
Dreaming?
Yeah. Don't tell me you don't dream?
Shinji...
Why's he lyin' here next to me?
Where am I?
In the same hospital as my sister?
Hey, isn't that Shinji and Ayanami?
Ikari, why did you do that?
Because I couldn't forgive my father.
He betrayed me.
I was finally able to have a comfortable
conversation with my father,
but he won't try to understand my feelings at all!
Did you try to understand your father's feelings?
I tried.
Why don't you try to understand him?
I said I tried!
And that's how you run away
from unpleasantness.
What's wrong with that?!
What's wrong with running away
from unpleasantness?!
What are those two arguin' about?
We're making a special exception for you.
Just for five minutes.
I understand. Thank you very much.
If it isn't the Class Rep...
Suzuhara, are you okay?
Well, looks like I'm still alive.
What the heck? I thought Shinji was here.
Was I just dreamin'?
I heard Ikari was discharged yesterday.
You've slept for three days, Suzuhara.
I did? For three whole days?
Class Rep, did you...
I came here as part of my duties
as the class representative!
There isn't anything else to it!
Yeah, I know that.
You don't know anything.
Sorry that I didn't get to eat
the lunch you made.
Don't worry about it.
But I'm sorry. They won't let me
bring you lunch here.
Class Rep?
What?
Would you do me a favor?
Would you tell my sister that there's
nothin' wrong with me?
Get out, Shinji Ikari.
The Commander wants to see you.
Disobeying orders, private
appropriation of an Eva,
blatant intimidation...
These are all criminal offenses.
Do you have anything to say?
Yes, I don't want to pilot an Eva anymore.
I don't want to stay here either.
Then leave.
Yes. I'll go back to my teacher's place.
So you're running away again?
You disappoint me.
I doubt we'll ever meet again.
Yes, that's my intent.
It's me.
Erase the Third Child.
Rei will be Unit 01's designated pilot,
with the dummy plug as backup.
Are you there, Shinji?
Is it true that you're leaving?
It's true, isn't it?
But why? Why are you running away now?
I wanted to be like you.
I envied you. You're different from us.
Damn! Even Toji became an Eva pilot, while I...
This line is monitored.
For security reasons, we have
terminated this call.
We appreciate your cooperation.
I'm sure that Asuka is so disgusted with me,
she's not coming.
Yes, she didn't even ask me
to say goodbye to you.
That sounds like her. I'm relieved.
If you keep cutting your ties like this,
you'll have a tough life ahead of you.
That's your philosophy, Miss Misato.
I can't live like you.
As I'm sure you know,
there will be quite a few restrictions
placed on your activities.
Yes.
But...
What?
Please tell me one thing.
Why was Toji chosen to be the Fourth Child?
All the fourth-level candidates
were in your class.
I just found out myself recently
that it was all set up.
All of them?
All of my classmates...
What happened with Suzuhara was a mistake
that can't be mended with words alone.
But, Shinji, to be honest,
I was projecting all of my dreams,
hopes and purpose onto you.
I also know that it's been a huge burden for you.
But we, everyone at Nerv,
had no choice except to entrust
our future to you.
I want you to remember that one thing.
That's a selfish excuse, isn't it?
I know it is.
I'll leave your pass code to HQ
and your room as they are.
There's no point. Get rid of them, please.
I won't pilot an Eva again.
He's speaking aggressively.
I've never heard him like that.
Government Only Special Express R-13
Departing 13:38 to New Atsugi
A special state of emergency has been declared
for the Tokai region.
Evacuation Route
All residents, please evacuate to your
designated shelters immediately.
Repeating...
An Angel!
All personnel, battle stations, Level One.
Prepare for ground-to-air intercept.
Target status?
It's currently advancing.
The Komagatake Defense Line
has been penetrated.
Armor layers one through eighteen
have been breached!
Eighteen layers of special armor at once?!
The Eva won't make it there in time
for a ground level intercept.
Position Unit 02 for combat
inside the Geo-Front,
directly in front of Headquarters.
Asuka will engage the target as soon
as it breaches the Geo-Front.
What about Unit 00?
It's been placed in the AT Field
Neutralization Zone.
However, the left arm hasn't been
regenerated yet.
Then it can't engage in combat.
Sortie Rei in Unit 01.
Prepare a dummy plug as the backup system.
Yes, Sir.
Start entry.
LCL electrolyzed.
Commence A10 nerve connection.
So it's not going to work anymore.
Pulse flow is reversing!
Unit 01 is rejecting the neural connections!
No, that can't be possible!
Ikari?
Yes, it's rejecting me.
Abort activation. Sortie Rei in Unit 00.
Re-activate Unit 01 with the dummy plug.
But Unit 00 isn't...
It doesn't matter. I'll go.
Rei?
Even if I die, I can be replaced.
I... I decided I'd never pilot it again.
Hey, you! What're you doing?
Get into the shelter, quickly.
It's no use!
One more hit, and all the armor layers
will have been breached!
I'm counting on you, Asuka.
Here it comes.
Even if Shinji isn't here, I can do this by myself.
Piece of cake!
Bastard!
Darn. Next!
I'm neutralizing its AT Field, aren't I?
Why won't it go down?!
I can't lose ever again!
No way!
You damn bastard!
Asuka!
Cut all the nerve connections now!
Evacuation training? What are you, stupid?
That stuff's got nothing to do with us pilots.
Direct hit on the Eighth District!
Abandon the Sixth Shelter! All survivors,
hurry to the Third Shelter!
Unit 02 is severely damaged!
It can't continue combat.
How's Asuka?
She's safe. Alive!
Damn...
The Angel has started moving.
What's Unit 01's status?
Dummy plug upload, complete.
Probe insertion, complete.
Start contact.
Roger!
What?
The pulses have vanished.
It's rejecting the dummy plug.
It's no use! Eva Unit 01 won't activate!
The dummy, Rei...
It won't accept them?
Fuyutsuki...
I'm leaving you in charge for a bit.
Number two and number four will be blocked off.
Please evacuate immediately.
Take casualties to the Sixth Block.
Hurry the uninjured to the Third Shelter!
This way!
Hurry!
Quickly!
Hey, you! What're you doing?
Do you want to die?!
Asuka...
Well, if it isn't Shinji.
Mr. Kaji?
What are you doing here?
That's my line.
What are you doing here, Shinji?
I...
I'm never going to pilot an Eva again.
And since I decided that...
I see.
Well, since my moonlighting came out into
the open, I'm not welcome on the combat roster.
So, here I am, watering the plants.
At a time like this?
It's because it's a time like this.
Between Katsuragi's breasts is nice too,
but in the end, I want to be here when I die.
Die?
That's right.
It's said if an Angel makes contact
with Adam, who lies below here,
humanity will be eradicated in the Third Impact.
The only thing that can stop it
is the one thing with power equal
to an Angel's, the Evangelion.
Ayanami?
Without even a rifle?!
Does she mean to blow herself up?!
Rei!
AT Field, full power.
What happened to Unit 00?
Rei!
What has she done?
Shinji, the only thing I can do
is stand here and water.
But you, you have something that you can do.
That only you can do.
Nobody is forcing you.
Think for yourself, and make
the decision by yourself.
Think about what you ought to do now.
You know, so you don't have any regrets.
Direct hit on the third foundation.
The final armor plate has melted!
Damn! The Main Shaft is completely exposed!
Isn't Unit 01 ready yet?
It's rejecting the dummy plug.
It failed! No response detected!
Keep trying. Repeat the process from step 108.
Let me pilot it!
I... I...
Let me pilot Unit 01, please!
Father...
Why are you here?
I... I...
I am the pilot of Evangelion Unit 01!
Shinji Ikari!
The target has invaded the Main Shaft!
It's descending!
Where is it heading?
It's advancing directly towards Central Dogma.
It's coming here.
All personnel evacuate. Hurry!
All personnel evacuate!
Repeat, all personnel evacuate!
Eva Unit 01?!
Shinji!
Miss Misato!
Launch number five! Hurry!
Out of energy?
Unit 01 has reached its activation limit.
The backup isn't working either!
Shinji!
Move! Move! Move! Move! Come on, move!
There isn't any point to this
if you don't move now!
That's...
Move! Move! Move!
Move! Move! Move! Move! Move! Move!
Move! Move! Come on, move!
If you don't move now, if you don't do it now,
everyone's going to die!
I don't want any more of that! So...
PLEASE MOVE!
Eva has re-activated!
Incredible!
No way, this is unbelievable.
Unit 01's synch rate is over 400%!
Does that mean she's really awakened?
It's eating the Angel?
Eva Unit 01 is taking the S2 engine into herself?
The bindings!
Bindings?
That's right. That's not armor plating.
Those are restraints that allow us
to suppress the Eva's true power.
And now those bindings are being undone
by the Eva's own might.
We can no longer stop the Eva.
Unit 01's been awakened and set free.
Seele won't stay quiet for this.
Was this also part of your script,
Commander Ikari?
It's begun, hasn't it?
Yes, it all begins here.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Mankind has been saved
by the Eva's awakening,
but Shinji is taken into Unit 01
and merges with it physically.
They try to salvage him, but fail.
What was it that the crying Misato saw?
Next time: "Form of the Mind,
Form of the Man"
FORM OF THE MIND, FORM OF THE MAN